Register of the Jacques Leprette papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Ministère des Affaires Étrangères File, 1946-2000
  - Adjoint-administrateur, Direction d'Europe
    - Printed matter, 1946-1949
      - Serial issue, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 54: 9)
        Selected numbers of Notes documentaires et études
    - Reports, 1947 (Box-folder 54: 10)
  - Conseiller, Secrétariat général du Conseil de l'Europe
    - Conference program, 1951 (Box-folder 55: 1)
    - Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box-folder 55: 2)
    - Instructions, 1949 (Box-folder 55: 3)
    - Memoranda and transcripts of proceedings
      Includes some related correspondence
      - 1949 (Box-folder 55: 4)
      - 1950 (Box-folder 55: 5-6)
      - 1951 (Box-folder 55: 7)
      - 1952 (Box-folder 55: 8)
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 55: 9)
    - Printed matter, 1949-1951
      - Clipping, 1949 (Box-folder 55: 10)
      - Council of Europe proceedings and related documents (in English and French)
        - Committee of Ministers
          - First session, 1949 August 8-13 (Box-folder 56: 1)
          - Second session, 1949 November 3-5 (Box-folder 56: 2)
          - Fifth session, 1950 August 3-9 (Box-folder 56: 3)
          - Sixth session, 1950 November 3-4 (Box-folder 56: 4)
          - Seventh session, 1951 March 16-17 (Box-folder 56: 5)
          - Eighth session, 1951 May 2-4 (Box-folder 56: 6)
        - Consultative Assembly
          - First session, 1949 August 10 - September 8 (Box-folder 56: 7)
          - Ordinary session, 1950 August 7-28; November 18-24 (Box-folder 56: 8)
          - Protocol, 1950 December 23 (Box-folder 57: 1)
          - Third ordinary session
            - First part, 1951 May 5-15 (Box-folder 57: 2-3)
            - Second part, 1951 November 26 - December 11 (Box-folder 57: 4)
          - Indexes, 1949-1951 (Box-folder 57: 5)
      - Pamphlet, 1951 (Box-folder 57: 6)
      - Serial issue, 1949 May 5 (Box-folder 57: 7)
  - Chef de la division politique, Gouvernement militaire français de Berlin
    - Communiqués, memoranda, transcripts of meetings, and reports
      - General, 1950-1954 (Box-folder 58: 1)
      - Conferences and meetings
        - Berlin airspace, 1953 August 14 (Box-folder 58: 2)
        - Foreign ministers of the four occupying powers, 1954 January-February (Box-folder 58: 3-5)
        - High commissioners, 1954 January 11-16 (Box-folder 58: 6)
    - Correspondence
      - 1952 (Box-folder 58: 7)
      - 1953 (Box-folder 58: 8)
      - 1954 (Box-folder 58: 9)
      - 1955 (Box-folder 58: 10)
    - Course materials, 1954 (Box-folder 58: 11)
    - Diplomatic passes and authorizations, 1955 (Box-folder 58: 12)
    - Personnel file, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 59: 1)
    - Printed matter
      - Bulletins and digests, 1953 (Box-folder 59: 2)
      - Serial issues, 1954 (Box-folder 59: 3)
    - Protocol, 1952 July 26 (Box-folder 59: 4)
    - Subject file, 1953-1954
      Bulletins, clippings, digests, map, memoranda, notes, and reports
      - Germany (East)--History--Uprising, 1953
        - Clippings, 1953 (Box-folder 59: 5-6)
        - Map showing locations of strikes in East Germany, 1953 (Box-folder 59: 7)
        - News digests and newswire bulletins, 1953 (Box-folder 59: 8)
        - Notes by Leprette, 1953 (Box-folder 59: 9)
        - Official memoranda, 1953 (Box-folder 59: 10)
      - London accords, 1954 (Box-folder 59: 11)
      - Paris accords, 1954 (Box-folder 59: 12)
      - Reuter, Ernst, 1953 (Box-folder 59: 13)
  - Conseiller, Ambassade de France, Washington, D.C
    - Clipping and newswire report, undated and 1959 (Box-folder 59: 14)
    - Commission des Caraïbes materials, 1953-1959
      - Correspondence and memoranda
        - 1957 (Box-folder 59: 15)
        - 1958 (Box-folder 59: 16)
        - 1959 (Box-folder 60: 1)
      - Declaration, 1956 (Box-folder 60: 2)
      - Serial issue, 1953 October 22 (Box-folder 60: 3)
      - Study, 1959 (Box-folder 60: 4)
        Includes related correspondence
    - Correspondence
      - General
        - 1955 (Box-folder 60: 5)
        - 1956 (Box-folder 60: 6)
        - 1957 (Box-folder 60: 7)
        - 1958 (Box-folder 60: 8)
        - 1959 (Box-folder 60: 9)
        - 1960 (Box-folder 60: 10)
      - Dispatches and memoranda
        - 1955-1956 (Box-folder 60: 11)
        - 1957 (Box-folder 60: 12)
        - 1958 (Box-folder 61: 1)
        - 1959
          - January-June (Box-folder 61: 2)
          - July-October (Box-folder 61: 3)
    - Diplomatic passes, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 61: 4)
    - Notes
      - 1957-1958 (Box-folder 61: 5)
      - 1959-1960 (Box-folder 61: 6)
    - Personnel file, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 61: 7)
    - Press releases, 1956 (Box-folder 61: 8)
    - Report, 1960 (Box-folder 61: 9)
    - Schedule, undated (Box-folder 61: 10)
    - Speeches
      - "Cérémonie à la mémoire de Béchet de Rochefontaine,", 1955 May 6 (Box-folder 61: 11)
      - "The New Neutralism," Portland, Oregon, 1955 June 4 (Box-folder 61: 12)
      - "Exposé sur la politique française," Andes Forum, Andes, New York, 1955 June 6 (Box-folder 61: 13)
      - Debate organized by World Affairs Council Institute of International Relations, Portland, Oregon, 1955 June 13
        - Correspondence and memoranda (Box-folder 61: 14)
        - Typescript (Box-folder 61: 15)
      - Sixth Conference on Problems of American Foreign Policy, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana, 1955 June 24-25 (Box-folder 62: 1)
        Correspondence, memorandum, and program only
      - Speech commemorating French military's role in the American Revolution, Newport, Rhode Island, 1955 June 29 (Box-folder 62: 2)
        List, notes, and typescript
      - "France and the North African Problem," Secondary School Society for International Cooperation, Cheshire, Connecticut, 1955 October 30
        - Correspondence (Box-folder 62: 3)
        - Typescripts (French and English versions) (Box-folder 62: 4)
      - Speech on early French explorers, Society of Pioneers, Indianapolis, Indiana, 1955 December 1 (Box-folder 62: 5)
      - "Some Trends in Contemporary French Thought," Texas Christian University, Fort Worth, Texas, 1955 December 3
        - Correspondence and clippings (Box-folder 62: 6)
        - Typescripts (French and English versions) (Box-folder 62: 7)
      - "France and the North African Problem," Trinity College, Hartford, Connecticut, 1955 December 12 (Box-folder 62: 8)
        Typescript and memorandum
      - Television message, 1956 January 1 (Box-folder 62: 9)
      - "French Policy in North Africa," Sweet Briar College, Sweet Briar, Virginia, 1956 February 21
        - Correspondence and memorandum (Box-folder 62: 10)
        - Typescript (Box-folder 62: 11)
      - Conference on American Foreign Policy, Colgate University, Hamilton, New York, 1956 July 3-5 (Box-folder 62: 12)
        Correspondence and program only
      - Speech on French policy in Africa, Western Michigan College, Kalamazoo, Michigan, 1956 November 13-16 (Box-folder 62: 13)
      - Speech on French policy in Africa, Cooperative Forum, Washington, D.C., 1957 January 30
        - Correspondence (Box-folder 62: 14)
        - Typescript (Box-folder 62: 15)
      - Rising Influences in Central Africa conference, Western Michigan College, Kalamazoo, Michigan, 1957 July 9-13 (Box-folder 62: 16)
      - Talk, Watson School of International Affairs, Lafayette College, Easton, Pennsylvania, 1957 December 12 (Box-folder 62: 17)
        Correspondence only
      - Speech on French policy in Africa, Northwestern University, Evanston, Illinois, 1958 March 3
        - Correspondence (Box-folder 62: 18)
        - Typescript (Box-folder 62: 19)
      - Speech on French policy in Africa, Northwestern University, Evanston, Illinois, 1959 February 23 (Box-folder 62: 20)
        Typescripts (French and English version) and list of participants
      - "National Self-Determination and French Policy in the Overseas Territories after World War II," Georgetown University, Washington, D.C., 1959 April 25 (Box-folder 63: 1)
      - "French Policy in Africa," Earlham College, Richmond, Indiana, 1959 May 1 (Box-folder 63: 2)
    - Subject file
      Brochures, bulletins, clippings, lists, memoranda, and reports
      - Africa--History--20th century, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 63: 3-4)
      - Civil rights movements--United States, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 63: 5)
      - Colonialism--20th century, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 63: 6)
      - Geneva Conference, 1955 (Box-folder 63: 7)
      - Press--United States, 1949-1953 (Box-folder 63: 8)
    - Travel file
      - General, 1955-1988 (Box-folder 63: 9)
        Receipts and forms
      - Algeria, 1958 (Box-folder 63: 10)
        Correspondence, map, memorandum, notes, and schedule
  - Chef du Service des Affaires de la Communauté
    - Clippings and newswire report, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 64: 1)
    - Correspondence
      - 1960 (Box-folder 64: 2)
      - 1961 (Box-folder 64: 3)
    - Notes, 1961 (Box-folder 64: 4)
    - Organisation Commune des Régions Sahariennes materials
      - Correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 64: 5)
      - Memoranda, reports, and transcripts of proceedings
        - 1960 (Box-folder 64: 6)
        - 1961 (Box-folder 64: 7)
      - Maps, 1959 (Box-folder 64: 8)
    - Personnel file, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 64: 9)
    - Reports, 1960 (Box-folder 64: 10)
    - Study on the Sahara, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 64: 11)
    - Subject file, 1957-1960
      Correspondence, memoranda, pamphlets, and transcripts of proceedings
      - Algeria--Economic conditions, 1957 (Box-folder 65: 1)
      - Côte d'Ivoire--Politics and government, 1961 (Box-folder 65: 2)
      - Lecannelier, Jean, 1960 (Box-folder 65: 3)
  - Ambassadeur, Nouakchott, Mauritania
    - Administrative file, 1962-1963
      Correspondence, financial records, lists, reports, and statistics
      - Budgets and finances
        - 1962 (Box-folder 65: 4)
        - 1963 (Box-folder 65: 5)
      - Buildings, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 65: 6)
      - Consulate at Port-Étienne, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 65: 7)
      - Correspondence, 1962-1963
        - Boyer, Gaston, circa 1962 (Box-folder 65: 8)
        - Société Anonyme des Mines de Fer de Mauritanie (MIFERMA), 1962-1963 (Box-folder 65: 9)
      - Departure ceremonies, 1963 (Box-folder 65: 10)
      - Education and training, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 65: 11)
      - Lists of recipients of awards and decorations, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 66: 1)
      - Military affairs, 1962 (Box-folder 66: 2)
      - Official visits, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 66: 3)
      - Personnel
        - General, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 66: 4)
        - Leprette, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 66: 5)
    - Chronology, 1961 (Box-folder 66: 6)
    - Clippings, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 66: 7)
    - Correspondence and memoranda
      - 1960 (Box-folder 66: 8)
      - 1961 (Box-folder 66: 9)
        - January-March (Box-folder 66: 10)
        - April-June (Box-folder 66: 11)
        - July-December (Box-folder 67: 1)
      - 1963
        - January-June (Box-folder 67: 2)
        - July-December (Box-folder 67: 3)
    - Intelligence data, largely relating to political activists in Mauritania, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 67: 4)
    - Notes, 1962 (Box-folder 67: 5)
    - Reports
      - General, 1962 (Box-folder 67: 6-7)
      - General, 1962 (Box-folder 68: 1)
      - By Leprette, 1963 (Box-folder 68: 2)
    - Serial issues, 1963 (Box-folder 68: 3)
    - Summaries and transcripts of meetings, 1961-1962
      - Charles de Gaulle, 1961 (Box-folder 68: 4)
      - Moktar Ould Daddah, 1962 (Box-folder 68: 5)
  - Ministre-Conseiller, Ambassade de France, Washington, D.C
    - Administrative file, 1964-1971
      Correspondence, memoranda, and reports
      - Alliance Française, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 68: 6)
      - Association Amicale des Affaires Étrangères, 1966 (Box-folder 68: 7)
      - Consulates
        - Chicago, 1964-1967 (Box-folder 68: 8)
        - Los Angeles, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 68: 9)
        - New Orleans, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 68: 10)
        - San Francisco, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 69: 1)
      - Entertainment, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 69: 2)
      - Internships, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 69: 3)
      - Official visits
        - General, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 69: 4)
        - Jacques Leprette
          - 1967 (Box-folder 69: 5)
          - 1968 (Box-folder 69: 6)
          - 1970 (Box-folder 69: 7)
        - Charles Lucet, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 69: 8)
        - Alain Peyrefitte, 1970 (Box-folder 69: 9)
        - Georges Pompidou, 1970 (Box-folder 69: 10-11)
        - Georges Pompidou, 1970 (Box-folder 70: 1-3)
      - Personal travel, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 70: 4)
      - Personnel
        - 1966-1968 (Box-folder 70: 5)
        - 1969 (Box-folder 70: 6)
        - 1970-1971 (Box-folder 70: 7)
    - Bulletin, 1966 (Box-folder 71: 1)
    - Clippings, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 71: 2)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1971
      - A (Box-folder 71: 3)
      - B (Box-folder 71: 4-5)
      - C (Box-folder 71: 6)
      - D (Box-folder 71: 7)
      - E (Box-folder 71: 8)
      - F (Box-folder 71: 9)
      - G (Box-folder 71: 10)
      - H (Box-folder 72: 1)
      - I (Box-folder 72: 2)
      - J (Box-folder 72: 3)
      - K (Box-folder 72: 4)
      - L (Box-folder 72: 5-6)
      - M (Box-folder 72: 7)
      - N (Box-folder 72: 8)
      - O (Box-folder 72: 9)
      - P (Box-folder 72: 10)
      - R (Box-folder 72: 11)
      - S (Box-folder 72: 12)
      - T (Box-folder 72: 13)
      - V (Box-folder 72: 14)
      - W (Box-folder 73: 1)
      - Z (Box-folder 73: 2)
    - Diplomatic passes, 1970 (Box-folder 73: 2)
    - Memoranda and summaries of meetings
      - 1966 (Box-folder 73: 4-5)
      - 1967 (Box-folder 73: 6-7)
      - 1968 (Box-folder 73: 8-9)
      - 1969 (Box-folder 73: 10)
      - 1970-1971 (Box-folder 73: 11)
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 74: 1)
    - Pamphlet, 1966 (Box-folder 74: 2)
    - Press releases and news bulletins, 1966-1967
    - Speeches
      - General, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 74: 4)
      - By Charles Lucet
        - 1966 (Box-folder 74: 5)
        - 1967 (Box-folder 74: 6)
      - By Jacques Leprette
        - Yorktown Day address, 1966 October 17 (Box-folder 74: 7)
        - Remarks, embassy dinner, Washington, D.C., 1967 January 6 (Box-folder 74: 8)
        - Welcoming speech, "April in Paris" ball, New York City, 1967 October 27 (Box-folder 74: 9)
        - Remarks, embassy dinner, 1968 January 5 (Box-folder 74: 10)
        - Remarks, embassy dinner, 1968 December 31 (Box-folder 74: 11)
        - Remarks, embassy dinner, 1969 January 8 (Box-folder 74: 12)
        - "French Foreign Policy," Kiwanis Club, Kingsport, Tennessee, 1969 September 12 (Box-folder 74: 13)
        - "France and the Common Market," Rotary International, Frankfort, Kentucky (Box-folder 74: 14)
        - "French Foreign Policy," University of Louisville, Louisville, Kentucky, 1969 October 24 (Box-folder 74: 15)
        - Remarks, embassy dinner, 1971 January 5 (Box-folder 74: 16)
    - Subject file
      Clippings, notes, pamphlets, and serial issues
      - France--Politics and government, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 75: 1)
      - Karlin, George, 1970 (Box-folder 75: 2)
      - Kennedy, Robert, 1968 (Box-folder 75: 3)
      - United States--Politics and government, 1968 (Box-folder 75: 4-6)
  - Directeur des Nations Unies et Organisations Internationales, 1971-1975
    - Administrative file
      - Personal travel, 1972 (Box-folder 75: 7)
      - Personnel
        - 1971-1973 (Box-folder 75: 8)
        - 1974 (Box-folder 75: 9)
      - Seminars, 1972 (Box-folder 75: 10)
    - Clippings, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 75: 11)
    - Conferences, meetings, and official visits file
      Correspondence, memoranda, notes, and reports
      - General
        - Visit of Jacques Leprette, London, England, 1971 May 4 (Box-folder 75: 12)
        - Meeting between French and Soviet diplomats, Leningrad, 1971 September 2 (Box-folder 75: 13)
        - Visit of Soviet delegation, Paris, France, 1972 June 27-28 (Box-folder 75: 14)
        - Visit of Chiao Kuan-Hua, Paris, France, 1972 November 17-20 (Box-folder 76: 1)
        - Visit of Kurt Waldheim, Paris, France, 1973 April 10 (Box-folder 76: 2)
        - Meeting between French and Soviet diplomats, 1973 September 3 (Box-folder 76: 3)
        - Visit of Michel Jobert, New York City, 1973 September 23-28 (Box-folder 76: 4)
        - Meeting between French and British diplomats, 1974 January 4 (Box-folder 76: 5)
        - Visit of Jacques Leprette, Bonn, West Germany, 1974 May 21 (Box-folder 76: 6)
      - United Nations
        - General
          - Food and Agriculture Organization meeting, Rome, Italy, 1971 June 7-18 (Box-folder 76: 7)
          - Conference on the Human Environment, Stockholm, Sweden, 1972 June 5-16 (Box-folder 76: 8)
          - Geneva Group meeting, Geneva, Switzerland, 1974 February 5-6 (Box-folder 76: 9)
        - General Assembly sessions
          - 1971 (Box-folder 76: 10)
          - 1972 (Box-folder 76: 11-12)
          - 1974 (Box-folder 76: 13)
        - Security Council meetings
          - 1972 (Box-folder 76: 14)
          - 1973 (Box-folder 76: 15)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1975
      - A (Box-folder 77: 1)
      - B (Box-folder 77: 2)
      - C (Box-folder 77: 3)
      - D (Box-folder 77: 4)
      - E (Box-folder 77: 5)
      - F (Box-folder 77: 6)
      - G (Box-folder 77: 7-8)
      - H (Box-folder 77: 9)
      - I (Box-folder 77: 10)
      - J (Box-folder 78: 1)
      - K (Box-folder 78: 2)
      - L (Box-folder 78: 3-4)
      - M (Box-folder 78: 5)
      - N (Box-folder 78: 6)
      - P (Box-folder 78: 7)
      - Q (Box-folder 78: 8)
      - R (Box-folder 78: 9)
      - S (Box-folder 78: 10)
      - T (Box-folder 78: 11)
      - U (Box-folder 78: 12)
      - V (Box-folder 78: 13)
      - W-Z (Box-folder 78: 14)
    - Memoranda and reports
      - 1971 (Box-folder 79: 1-2)
      - 1972 (Box-folder 79: 3-4)
      - 1973 (Box-folder 79: 5-6)
      - 1974 (Box-folder 79: 7-9)
      - 1975 (Box-folder 80: 1)
    - Notes, 1972 (Box-folder 80: 2)
    - Speeches by Michel Jobert, 1973 (Box-folder 80: 3-4)
      Includes related correspondence and memoranda
    - Subject file
      Brochures, pamphlets, and serial issues
      - Military policy--France, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 80: 5-6)
      - Universal Declaration of Human Rights, 1973 (Box-folder 80: 7)
  - Directeur adjoint des Affaires Politiques
    - Administrative file
      Correspondence, clipping, and memoranda
      - Angelo Cagnoni affair, 1975 (Box-folder 81: 1)
      - Personnel, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 81: 2)
    - Comité Français du Bicentenaire de l'Indépendence des États-Unis materials
      - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports
        - 1971 (Box-folder 81: 3)
        - 1972 (Box-folder 81: 4)
        - 1973 (Box-folder 81: 5)
        - 1974 (Box-folder 81: 6)
        - 1975
          - January-June (Box-folder 81: 7)
          - July-December (Box-folder 81: 8)
        - 1976
          - January-March (Box-folder 81: 9)
          - April-October (Box-folder 82: 1)
      - Invitations, 1976 (Box-folder 82: 2)
      - Printed matter, 1958-1976 (Box-folder 82: 3)
      - Speeches relating to the bicentennial delivered by Valéry Giscard d'Estaing, 1976 (Box-folder 82: 4)
      - Summaries of meetings
        - 1971-1972 (Box-folder 82: 5)
        - 1973-1974 (Box-folder 82: 6)
        - 1975-1976 (Box-folder 82: 7)
    - Conferences, meetings, and official visits file
      Correspondence, memoranda, notes, speech, and reports
      - Visit of Valéry Giscard d'Estaing, Zaire, 1975 August (Box-folder 82: 8)
      - Meeting of foreign ministers, Dublin, Ireland, 1976 April 1 (Box-folder 82: 9)
      - Ditchley Foundations conference, Ditchley Park, England, 1976 April 2-5 (Box-folder 82: 10)
      - Meeting on European political cooperation, The Hague, Netherlands, 1976 September 9-10 (Box-folder 82: 11)
      - Diplomatic mission conducted by Jacques Leprette, Vientiane, Laos, 1976 October 11-17 (Box-folder 83: 1-2)
    - Correspondence
      - General
        - 1975 (Box-folder 83: 3)
        - 1976 (Box-folder 83: 4)
      - Vaurs, Roger, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 83: 5)
    - Memoranda
      - 1975 (Box-folder 83: 6)
      - 1976 (Box-folder 83: 7)
    - Notes
      - 1975 (Box-folder 83: 8)
      - 1976 (Box-folder 83: 9)
  - Ambassadeur, United Nations
    - Administrative file
      - Directory, 1979 (Box-folder 83: 10)
      - Entertainment, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 83: 11)
      - Financial records, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 84: 1)
      - Guest book, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 84: 2)
      - Insurance, 1977 (Box-folder 84: 3)
      - Local information, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 84: 4)
      - Personal belongings, 1979 (Box-folder 84: 5)
      - Personal travel, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 84: 6)
      - Personnel, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 84: 7)
      - Residence, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 84: 8)
      - Residence, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 85: 1-2)
      - Schedules of meetings and engagements, 1976-1981
        - 1976 (Box-folder 85: 3)
        - 1977 (Box-folder 85: 4)
        - 1978
          - January-June (Box-folder 85: 5)
          - July-December (Box-folder 85: 6)
        - 1979
          - January-June (Box-folder 85: 7)
          - July-December (Box-folder 86: 1)
        - 1980
          - January-June (Box-folder 86: 2)
          - July-December (Box-folder 86: 3)
        - 1981
          - January-June (Box-folder 86: 4)
          - July-December (Box-folder 86: 5)
    - Biography, undated (Box-folder 86: 6)
    - Clippings and newswire reports, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 86: 7-8)
    - Conferences, meetings, and official visits file
      Clippings, correspondence, memoranda, notes, pamphlets, and reports
      - Meeting between Leprette and Kurt Waldheim, New York City(?), 1977 (Box-folder 86: 9)
      - Visit of Kurt Waldheim, Paris, France, 1977 July 7-8 (Box-folder 87: 1)
      - Talks on Namibia, New York City, 1977 August 8-11 (Box-folder 87: 2)
      - Bilateral consultations between French and Soviet diplomats, United Nations, New York City, 1977 September 13 (Box-folder 87: 3)
      - Visit of Louis de Guiringaud, New York City, 1977 September 25 - October 5 (Box-folder 87: 4)
      - Talks on Namibia, New York City, 1978 February 11-12 (Box-folder 87: 5-6)
      - Visit of École Normale d'Administration delegation, New York City, 1978 February 25 - March 11 (Box-folder 87: 7)
      - Visit of J. M. Merillon, New York City, 1978 February 28-March 2 (Box-folder 87: 8)
      - Visit of Valéry Giscard d'Estaing, New York City, 1978 May 24-26 (Box-folder 87: 9)
      - Visit of Valéry Giscard d'Estaing, New York City, 1978 May 24-26 (Box-folder 88: 1-8)
      - Meetings between Jacques Leprette and Valéry Giscard d'Estaing, New York City, 1978 May 24-26 (Box-folder 88: 9)
      - Visit of Louis de Guiringaud, New York City, 1978 July 27-28 (Box-folder 89: 1)
      - Visit of Louis de Guiringaud, New York City, 1978 September 24 - October 2 (Box-folder 89: 2-3)
      - Visit of Jean-Marie Merillon, New York City, 1978 September 24 - October 2 (Box-folder 89: 4)
      - Visit of Bertrand Dufourcq, New York City, 1978 September 24 - October 3 (Box-folder 89: 5)
      - Talks on Namibia, New York City, September 25 (Box-folder 89: 6)
      - Visit of Olivier Stirn, New York City, 1978 October 8-10 (Box-folder 89: 7)
      - Visit of Roger Vaurs, New York City, 1978 October 15-17 (Box-folder 89: 8)
      - Visit of French parliamentary delegation, New York City, 1978 November-December (Box-folder 89: 9)
      - "Negotiating the End of Conflicts: The Case of Namibia and Zimbabwe," conference, International Peace Academy, New Paltz, New York, 1978 November 17-19 (Box-folder 89: 10)
      - Visit of Jacques Leprette, San Antonio, Austin, and Houston, Texas, 1979 April 2-4 (Box-folder 89: 11)
      - Visit of Jacques Leprette, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1979 May 31 - June 1 (Box-folder 89: 12)